Binni Cordova

Career Summary

Binni has worked on creating mobile applications using Flutter and React Native for Android and iOS, and he has experience in connecting native SDK from Java and Swift.

He led a team and has experience producing front-end and back-end apps for more than 4 years, using Firebase and AWS Amazon.

He has knowledge in Atom Design, Clean Code, Pattern Design, Refactoring techniques, Unit tests, Integration tests, and better practices.

He's passionate about new technologies and has a participative attitude in code reviews.

Summary of Qualifications Skills:

•	Flut

- tter
- GetX
- AWS Amazon
- Firebase
- Lambda
- Bridge SDK
- ReactNative
- Hooks
- Redux TypeScript
- JavaScript
- Node.is

- Java
- Swift API SOAP
- API REST
- API GraphQL
- Unit Test **JEST**
- Git
- AppStore
- PlayStore

Languages

- Spanish (native speaker)
- Italian (advanced)

English (intermediate)

Career History

GLOBANT, Multinational

Ssr Web UI - Chile ITU BANK, REACT NATIVE Developer

- He has developed the modules to make transfers, onboarding, and manage users
- He has used REDUX to manage the state of the application
- He developed the screens, layouts, and components applying Atom Design
- He develops bridges to native code Java-Android and Swift-iOS
- He has created Unit Test to preserve the code quality in 90% of the coverage
- He has participated in refining the new features for the sprints SCRUM

PLATANITOS ECOMMERCE RETAIL, Lima, Perú

Leader Flutter Developer

- He developed the Payment Methods, using Mercado Pago and Kushki
- He implemented Firebase and AWS Amazon services in the app Platanitos
- He has worked using Algolia and CloudSearch to manage the product catalog
- He upgraded the application to Flutter 2.5 Null-Safety
- He has worked on deploying the app to PlayStore, AppStore, and AppGallery
- He has worked on developing unit tests and integration tests.
- He created the application eCommerce Platanitos using Flutter 1.27, and Material Design
- He has worked coordinating and helping the 3 developers in his team

Leader React Native Developer

Jul. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Mar. 2019 – Dec. 2021 Feb. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- He implemented Live Streaming video using MUX service
- He developed new API REST using Amazon ApiGateway, Lambda, Python3.8, and MySQL
- He optimized the application React Native, using JavaScript asynchronous code and increasing the accessibility of the design

Dec. 2021 - Now

• He has worked estimating and proposing new features and leading the 2 developers in his team

React Native Developer

Mar. 2020 - Jul. 2020

- He has worked on creating new features and components for the React Native Platanitos app
- He developed new API end-points using Amazon EC2, PHP, and MySQL

Web Developer

Mar. 2019 – Mar. 2020

- He has developed an API SOAP using Node.js and Express to validate XML documents, OSE SUNAT PERÚ
- He created a website using Laravel (PHP) to check a Sale Report and manage the documents to upload to SUNAT
- He developed a dashboard using Grafana, to see in Real-Time the state of ROUTERS in 170 Platanitos stores.
- He installed and deployed the ZKTECO Python Server, to manage 170 biometrics modules

GPI GRUPPO, Trentino, Italy

Mar. 2018 - Nov. 2018

Software Developer and Analyst

- He has developed health forms using AngularJS, JQuery, and Bootstrap4, to collaborate on creating NGH - Next Generation HIS software
- He has worked on creating Dashboard using Yii2 (PHP framework) to manage tickets in the company
- He develops templates to print data, using Jasper Studio and Java

Technical Professional in Computing and Informatics

Education

Udemy iOS 14 Build Apps Using Swift 5	May 2022 – Jul. 2022
Udemy , Lima, Perú React Native Advanced Concepts	May 2022 – Jul. 2022
Udemy , Lima, Perú Flutter Web Developer	July. 2021 – Dec. 2021
Udemy , Lima, Perú Flutter Advanced	May. 2021 – Nov. 2021
IESTP Trentino Juan Pablo II, Lima, Perú	Mar. 2013 – Dec. 2015